The CHARA array is a collection of six
وهو مجموعة من مجموعة chara ستة
telescopes that are arranged on the ground
التلسكوبات مرتبة على الارض
in an area that more or less kind of
في منطقة من اكثر او اقل
covers the area that a single large
ان يغطي مجال كبير واحد
telescope mirror would have. And what we
وماذا سالتلسكوب have.نا المراة
then have to do is to have relay optics—
ثم عليك القيام به هو ان تتبع — البصريات
many, many mirrors along
على العديد من المرايا
the way to effectively
بالمناسبة
move the beams as if the
وكما لو ان تنتقل الحزم
telescopes were all placed
كانت كل وضع التلسكوبات
lying on this optical mirror
الكذب على هذه المراة بصري
that we’re trying to synthesize.
اننا نحاول ’ اعادة توليف .
And that’s been the real problem
والتي كانت المشكلة الحقيقية ’ التلاميذ
with interferometry, being able to
مع interferometry , القدرة على
precisely control the beams of light to
بالتحديد للتحكم في حزم من الضوء
attain that synthesis of a single mirror.
ان تظل واحدة للمراة .
This is part of the daily
هذا هو جزء من اليومي
alignment check. Essentially we
المحاذاة check. اساسا نحن
send a laser beam backwards through the
ارسال شعاع الليزر الى الوراء عبر
system and check that it hits all the points
انه نظام وتضرب كل النقاط
that it needs to hit. One of
انه يحتاج الى hit. احد
the targets is right here.
الاهداف هو هنا .
Spot on.
على الفور .
It's very important that from the star all
انه مهم جدا ان كل من النجم
the way to the point inside the instrument
الطريق الى النقطة داخل الالة
where we bring the light beams together that
حيث نحضر الضوء الذي اشعاعات معا
the light travel time is exactly the same.
الضوء بنفس الوقت هو السفر .
Now because the telescopes are at different
الان لان التلسكوبات في مختلف
elevations and different parts of the mountain
العلاقات واجزاء مختلفة من الجبل
and the Earth is constantly rotating,
وباستمرار , الارض تدور
these paths are forever changing.
هذه هي مسارات للابد تغيير .
So we have to continuously adjust
لذا علينا بضبط
these paths within the instrument
هذه المسارات داخل الالة
using a thing called a delay line.
باستخدام شئ يسمى بتاخير .
In interferometry, timing is everything and
في كل شيء , والتوقيت interferometry
that means that we have to get the light from
هذا يعني انه علينا ان الضوء من
all six telescopes around the mountain
كل ستة التلسكوبات حول الجبل
into this room at the same time.
في هذه الغرفة في نفس الوقت .
While we can’t control the speed of light
بينما ’ تي يمكننا التحكم بسرعة الضوء
or the time it travels, what we can do is change
او يسافرها , ما يمكننا القيام به هو تغيير
the path length over which it travels.
على طول الطريق الذي يسافر .
And that’s what this long tunnel is for.
وهذا ما هذا النفق ’ التلاميذ لفترة طويلة .
These carts are optical trombones. Such
هذه هي مثل عربات trombones. البصري
that we can add and subtract path-length
يمكننا اضافة والتخلص من طول الطريق
and make the light from each of the
وكل من الضوء من
six telescopes arrive at the same time
ستة التلسكوبات الوصول في نفس الوقت
at the back end so that we collect
في النهاية الخلفية لاننا نجمع
the data to make our pictures.
البيانات لصنع صورنا .
The ability to make images with
القدرة على صنع الصور مع
interferometry is dependant upon
هو على interferometry dependant
how many telescopes
كم من التلسكوبات
you can put into the mix.
يمكنك ان تضعها في مزيج .
As you add more and more telescopes, you
عندما تضيف المزيد والمزيد من التلسكوبات ,
get to fill in more and more pieces of
شغل في الحصول على المزيد والمزيد من
this image that you're trying to
هذه الصورة التي تحاول
synthesize as if you had a big telescope.
توليف كما لو كان لديك تليسكوب كبير .